Hi.
Another great thing masking tape is for is for creating zebra stripes.
Which is very, very popular right now.
The way we create zebra stripes is.
I'm going to use the same tile except I'm going to use the opposite side.
So to do zebra stripes, all I'm going to do is take some masking tape, tear some off and then I'm just going to simply strip the masking tape in to sections.
And what I'm going to try to do is I'm going to try to tear it so that it ends in a point.
So we just tear it like that.
So I've got a little stripe here.
I'm going to attach that to my piece.
Smooth it out.
Then I'm going to do the same.
I'm going to tear some more.
This one's a bit longer and we'll just attach that down.
And smooth it out.
Now this time since I've been going this way?
I'm going to do some and go the opposite way.
Just to make it look a little bit more like a zebra.
That piece didn't really work out for me.
So I'll try it again.
So after we've done this a couple times all I'm simply going to do is paint 3 good coats of really whatever color you want.
You don't have to have black and white zebra.
You can have a neon purple and yellow zebra if you want.
You can have any zebra you can possibly imagine.
So, once we have a couple stripes all I'm simply going to do is start my painting.
So I've got a couple here.
Generally I would do a bit more.
Now, I'm actually going to use the same color.
We're going to have a turquoise zebra today.
So all I'm going to do is I'm going to dunk my paintbrush back in to my paint.
Make sure all my paint is smooth and simply paint directly on top of my tape.
This is really fun to do, not only on flat surfaces but on round.
I see these a lot on mugs and having the zebra stripes go up and down rather than horizontal it looks really, really great.
And you can do it on almost any, any piece.
Which is really, really nice.
You also don't have to have them just one or two colors.
You can introduce 3 or 4 colors by taping each section off.
Applying a different color underneath and then reapplying tap and adding more color.
So now, all I'm going to do is I'm going to remove my tape.
And wherever my tape was is actually going to stay white.
So when I remove my tape we can start to see the formation of the zebra stripes.
And, it's as simple as that.